So finally let's take a look at what
kinds of consistency are there. We know
that there is sequential consistency and
then there is a family of relaxed
consistency models which are allowed to
violate one or more of those four
ordering rules. And the models that have
actually been proposed and sometimes
used are called weak consistency,
processor consistency, release
consistency, lazy release consistency,
scope consistency, etc. There are
actually many many relax consistency
models, too many to actually explain
here. But the key to all of them is that
although they allow arbitrary
reorderings or maybe some reorderings
among data operations, all of them
support synchronization operations that
allow you to ensure that the ordering
that you really want in your program
gets to happen. Some of them do it by
doing something like the mync
operations. Some of them do it by using
more refined memory synchronization
operations. Some of them do it by
actually calling library functions that
are ensuring such ordering and so